

# **Prateek Jindal**

# Embedded Software Engineer

H

06 July 1995



Delhi/India



+91 8802538181



jindalprateek@aol.com

## About me —

I am an automotive embedded software engineer with 2 years of industry experience. I design highly optimized algorithms for various embedded boards/SOCs and desktops. I have worked on various multi-processing architectures to designed highly parallelized software that are more performance oriented for real time applications. I am an ambitious and industrious person. Continuous improvement and expanding my radius of understanding in the field is my mantrá.

## Skills —

Micro-controllers

Embedded protocols (UART, SPI, I2C, CAN)

C - Embedded C

Python

Bash(Shell)

MATLAB

**RTOS** 

**AUTOSAR** 

## Experience

2019-2021 Software Engineer

2017-2017 RnD Engineer

Lear Corporation

Devanya Enterprise

### Education

2018-2019	Post Graduaion Diploma in Embedded Systems CDAC ACTS	Pune, India
2013-2017	B.Tech. in Electronics and Communication Dr.APJAKTU (UPTU)	Uttar Pradesh, India
2012-2013	12th Standard (Physics, Chemistry, Maths) CBSE	Delhi, India
2010-2011	10th Standard	Delhi India

## Technical Expertise

CBSE

- Microcontrollers AVR ARM Cortex M Cortex R RTOS
- Embedded C Python MATLAB Shell Script
- USART/UART SPI I2C CAN
- MOTT REST

## Project Information

#### **Work Projects**

- -Lear ConfigurE+ Adaptive Seating System
- -Platform Seat Control Module

#### Post Grad Diploma Project

- -Vehicle exterior lighting system and dashboard control
- -Implementation of RTOS on 2 STM32F4 discovery boards
- -CAN communication between the two boards acting as dashboard control unit (ECU1) and rear control unit (ECU2)
- -UART communication with the PC acting as main dashboard

#### Bachelor's Project (Major)

- -Anti Theft System for Automobiles
- -Smart system to track a lost or stolen vehicle
- -GPS module, to track the location
- -GSM module, for communication with user

#### Bachelor's Project (Minor)

- -Smart Energy Meter
- -Track energy reading at real time
- -IOT/MQTT

#### Hobbies

-Fitness , Football , Basketball , Music , Travelling